Rosenthal, Gregory; Papers apap353
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Gregory Rosenthal Papers2011-2014
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Rosenthal, Gregory (Historian)
apap353
0.25 cubic ft.
This collection contains publications, flyers, and notes which document the Occupy Movement and Free University of New York City, as well as other issues affecting New Yorkers at the time.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Gregory Rosenthal donated his papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives in 2015. 2015
Biographical History
Gregory Rosenthal is currently an assistant professor of public history at Roanoke College. While pursuing his doctorate in history at the State University of New York at Stony Brook, Rosenthal was an activist with Occupy Wall Street in 2011-2012 and a co-organizer of the Free University of New York City, 2012-2014. Rosenthal received his master's degree in public history from the University at Albany.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials related to Gregory Rosenthal's involvement in various movements, such as Occupy Wall Street and the Free University of New York City. This includes publications of the movement such as issues of The Occupied Wall Street Journal from 2011-2012 and three non-Journal publications also relating to the Occupy movement. There are also papers discussing activities of the Graduate Student Employee's Union at the State University of New York at Stony Brook, which Rosenthal was a member of. The remainder of the collection consists of leaflets, pamphlets, or informational packets about the other various movements or organizations that Rosenthal was a part of.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Occupy movement--New York (State)--New York; Pamphlets; Leaflets (printed works); Posters; Handbills; Newspapers; Rosenthal, Gregory (Historian); State University of New York at Stony Brook
- Circulation and the New University, 2014 (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 1)
- Cooper Union, Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 2)
- CUNY, 2012; Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 3)
- Equality/99%, Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 4)
- Free University, 2012; 2014; Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 5)
- Graduate Student Employee's Union, 2012-2014; Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 6)
- Green Party, Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 7)
- Hurricane Sandy, Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 8)
- Labor Equality, May Day, 2012-2014; Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 9)
- Migration and Human Rights, Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 10)
- Monsanto, 2013; Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 11)
- New York Student Rising, Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 12)
- The Occupied Wall Street Journal, 2011-2012; Undated (Flat-file 1)
- Occupy DC, Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 13)
- Occupy the LIRR, Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 14)
- Occupy Publications, 2012; Undated (Flat-file 2)
- Occupy Wall Street, 2011-2012; 2014; Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 15)
- Presidential Election, 2012; Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 16)
- Pro-Peace/Anti-War Movements, 2013; Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 17)
- Spectra Pipeline, Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 18)
- Stony Brook University, 2012-2014; Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 19)
- Stop and Frisk, Police Brutality, 2012; Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 20)
- Tidal, Occupy Theory, Occupy Strategy, 2012 (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 21)
- Women's Rights, Undated (Box 1 (Gregory Rosenthal Papers), Folder 22)